<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Better</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Getting Better</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>d33 Troika Backgrounds for What Was Manila</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pitg-d33-backgrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pitg-d33-backgrounds/</guid>
      <description>I ripped characteres from KOTOR 2 to make Troika Backgrounds for the local post-apocalypse. Yay?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choom&#39;s Tomb, a fan-made adventure for Cyberpunk RED</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chooms-tomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chooms-tomb/</guid>
      <description>The scenario is inspired by the Gunfight at the Ok Corral. That shound be obvious to a number of folks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thundering Steps, Gear List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thundering-steps-gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thundering-steps-gear/</guid>
      <description>The Gear List for Thundering Steps</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ATTENTION: Relaunch of Smells Fishy, Jack!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/attn-sfj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/attn-sfj/</guid>
      <description>It never changes. Welcome to the post-apocalyptic land of the Kapitol Wastes! A land resistant to progress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thundering Steps, REVISED</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thundering-steps-revised/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thundering-steps-revised/</guid>
      <description>Revised rules for playing nomadic horse archers. Inspired by Brandon Yu&amp;rsquo;s Chaos Reigns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/intro/</guid>
      <description>Assumptions&#xD;#&#xD;Set in a speculative very near future where our mode of technology isn&amp;rsquo;t too different from today.&#xA;Yes, this is effectively a not-so-subtle nod to Twilight 2000 and The Country by Luke Gearing.&#xA;Yes, this is also based on a hypothetical future for my home country based on lived experiences. Yes, this was kind of depressing to write. No, I&amp;rsquo;m not always this cynical.&#xA;You can find the companion adventure Ten Hail Marys in the Dark on itch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Character Creation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/chargen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/chargen/</guid>
      <description>Assumptions&#xD;#&#xD;Start at 17 years of age. By the end of character creation, you&amp;rsquo;re assumed be a survivor in this world.&#xA;Each Skill adds a +1, +2, or +3 to a 2d6 roll. You only roll 2d6 when doing risky things like shooting a foe in a firefight or trying to pick a lock under duress. The number you need to beat is always an 8, no more, no less.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gear List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/gear-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/gear-list/</guid>
      <description>Gear&#xD;#&#xD;Currency? Backed by fucking what? There are semblances of it ever since the Landlords took control of factories. Bullets from them are like trickled down gold. Nonetheless, it&amp;rsquo;s still hearkening back to what we&amp;rsquo;ve completely lost. Keeping up appearances in these times is asinine.&#xA;Social credit&amp;rsquo;s back since all we really got is our word that we&amp;rsquo;ll repay at one point. If your word is shit, however, expect fists to your face in the foreseeable future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skirmishes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/skirmishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/skirmishes/</guid>
      <description>Please check out Night-Tripper by Chris P. Wolf! You can find the original rules for Skirmishes here. These rules were heavily inspired by what&amp;rsquo;s there.&#xA;Selective Use&#xD;#&#xD;Single rolls or just saying what happens are enough to resolve most conflicts. For more complex scenarios, use these combat rules.&#xA;Rounds&#xD;#&#xD;Combat is divided into rounds. Each round being a flash of time. Each character commits to only one action per round.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unknown Variable, Rules Lite Horror</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/unknown-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/unknown-variables/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted something other than Liminal Horror to run the games the way I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Coffee, a Practice Poem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/better-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/better-coffee/</guid>
      <description>Something I wrote on a whim about a past relationship and the growth thereafter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wanton Pinoy Spaghetti: Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-intro/</guid>
      <description>TTRPG rules for playing in the wild times of late 19th Century Colonial Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thundering Steps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thundering-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thundering-steps/</guid>
      <description>Rules for playing nomadic horse archers. Inspired by Chainmail and ODnD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ten Haily Marys in the Dark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/10-hm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/10-hm/</guid>
      <description>This Is&#xD;#&#xD;It&amp;rsquo;s an adventure originally by Roz Leahy. You can find it in the Violence Jam (2022). I could really feel the wretched parallels between the setting of their work, Ireland, and my home country.&#xA;The Church is a bit of a mixed bag here in that they&amp;rsquo;ve been both a source of humanity and abetted in depravity. Even with the separation of Church and State, power corrupts both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Found on the Road! No. 01</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fotr-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fotr-01/</guid>
      <description>A rundown of interesting things I&amp;rsquo;ve found, new and old!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sages and a Non-Vancian Magic System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sages/</guid>
      <description>A random magic system for use in your games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic Character Generation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-chargen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-chargen/</guid>
      <description>The fastest way to make a character.&#xA;Think of a character concept. Who are they in this time in history? A foreigner? A local? Regardless, they (and now by extension you) are in consistent company with a group of companions.&#xA;These companions are the other players (their characters) at the table. Think of how you all know each other in the world. Why are you as thick as thieves? Are you thieves?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making a Character with Lifepaths</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-lifepaths/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-lifepaths/</guid>
      <description>Basic Assumptions&#xD;#&#xD;This is a more involved way of making a character. I do find this method generally more enjoyable if the point is to not make disposable characters.&#xA;Your character begins at 18 years of age, untrained and inexperienced. By the end of character creation, you&amp;rsquo;re assumed to have either retired from your career in pursuit of other goals or began traveling while still practicing your preferred profession.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Sun and Its Shadows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sun-shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sun-shadow/</guid>
      <description>Something I wrote about past mistakes, the burden of memory, and an epiphany brought about by good company.&#xA;Remember when I was young? I rather not. The sins from then still stain the once ivory light I shine. Bright, unyielding naivete colored those movements. Wherever I went, my shadows inflicted pain, undeservingly— I am not asking for contrition, Father. I am unworthy, but I fetch a good price in the market.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gear in your Inventory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-gear/</guid>
      <description>Blades&#xD;#&#xD;Item Cost Remarks Balisong 5 Concealable Throwing Knife 3 Concealable Hunting Knife 8 Bolo 11 Kris 16 Cane Sword 27 Concealable Firearms&#xD;#&#xD;Item Cost Remarks Revolver 18 6 shots Derringer 15 2 shots, Concealable Semi-automatic Pistol 20 8 shots Coach Gun 28 2 shots, quick reload, uses buckshot and slugs Pump-action Shotgun 37 6 shots, uses buckshot and slugs Lever-action Rifle 35 9 shots on hunting ammo, 14 shots on revolver ammo Single-shot Rifle 22 1 shot, quick reload, uses hunting or rifle ammo Bolt-Action Rifle 45 5 Shots, quick reload, uses rifle ammo Speed Loader 8 quick reload for revolver Revolver Ammunition 2 18 rounds, 1 slot Pistol Ammunition 3 24 rounds, 1 slot Hunting Ammunition 5 12 rounds, 1 slot Rifle Ammunition 8 15 rounds, 1 slot Buckshot 10 14 rounds, 1 slot Slugs 12 14 rounds, 1 slot Tools and Misc&#xD;#&#xD;Item Cost Remarks 15m Manila Rope 2 Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Bag 35 Grappling Hook 8 Leather Rucksack 8 Lockpicking Set 5 Spyglass 10 Ration 2 1 day&amp;rsquo;s worth Saddle 20 Salakot 5 Animals&#xD;#&#xD;Livestock&#xD;#&#xD;Item Cost Remarks Native Cattle 50 Imported Cattle 100 Pig 18 breeds fast Goat 35 Chicken 8 Fine Fighting Cock 175 Beasts of Burden&#xD;#&#xD;Item Price Description Pack Horse 50 all horses carry 15 slots Race Horse 100 for riding quickly over far distances War Horse 375 trained for combat and to trample over others Donkey 25 carries 10 slots, draft animal, but not as hardy Carabao 20 carries 30 slots, draft animal Camel 450 carries 20 slots, riding or pack animal Cart 100 allows for 80 slots while hitched to a draft beast Wagon 250 allows for 250 slots while hitched to a draft beast Carriage 325 allows for 150 slots while hitched to a draft beast Animals hitched may pull 4x their slots, but require a road to pass through mountains, forests, swamps, or desert terrain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wanton Pinoy Spaghetti: Violence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wps/wps-violence/</guid>
      <description>Based on Luke Gearing&amp;rsquo;s Violence!&#xA;Initiative&#xD;#&#xD;Roll a d20 for each individual or group involved in the combat. Write these down and resolve, highest first.&#xA;Do this at the beginning of each Round. A Round is an innumerably fast amount of time. A single moment between life and death.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;ve caught your opponents by surprise, you all shoot first and resolve Initiative after the players&amp;rsquo; turns.&#xA;Groups can be used for larger scale actions involving, for example, 3&amp;ndash;4 bands per “side” of a conflict.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
