<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bloody-Lands on Getting Better</title><link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/</link><description>Recent content in Bloody-Lands on Getting Better</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01 Introduction</title><link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/intro/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="assumptions">Assumptions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Set in a speculative very near future where our mode of technology isn&amp;rsquo;t too different from today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, this is effectively a not-so-subtle nod to Twilight 2000 and The Country by Luke Gearing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, this is also based on a hypothetical future for my home country based on lived experiences. Yes, this was kind of depressing to write. No, I&amp;rsquo;m not always this cynical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the companion adventure &lt;a href="https://san-tagoy.itch.io/ten-hail-marys-in-the-dark">Ten Hail Marys in the Dark on itch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Character Creation</title><link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/chargen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/chargen/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="assumptions">Assumptions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Start at 17 years of age&lt;/strong>. By the end of character creation, you&amp;rsquo;re assumed be a survivor in this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each &lt;strong>Skill&lt;/strong> adds a +1, +2, or +3 to a 2d6 roll. You only roll 2d6 when doing risky things like shooting a foe in a firefight or trying to pick a lock under duress. The number you need to beat is always an 8, no more, no less.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gear List</title><link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/gear-list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/gear-list/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="gear">Gear&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currency? Backed by fucking what? There are semblances of it ever since the Landlords took control of factories. Bullets from them are like trickled down gold. Nonetheless, it&amp;rsquo;s still hearkening back to what we&amp;rsquo;ve completely lost. Keeping up appearances in these times is asinine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social credit&amp;rsquo;s back since all we really got is our word that we&amp;rsquo;ll repay at one point. If your word is shit, however, expect fists to your face in the foreseeable future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skirmishes</title><link>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/skirmishes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/bloody-lands/skirmishes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please check out Night-Tripper by Chris P. Wolf! You can find the original rules for Skirmishes &lt;a href="https://www.night-tripper.fun/chapters/rules-for-play/skirmishes/">here&lt;/a>. These rules were heavily inspired by what&amp;rsquo;s there.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="selective-use">Selective Use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Single rolls or just saying what happens are enough to resolve most conflicts. For more complex scenarios, use these combat rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="rounds">Rounds&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Combat is divided into rounds. Each round being a flash of time. Each character commits to only one action per round. Resolve actions in the following order:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>